onlinemerchantforum.com 2011-06-03

# Announcements - Announcements

> **Because the ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM gathers certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it.** **COMMITMENT TO YOUR PRIVACY**  
>  This site is owned and operated by ABOUND ENTERPRISES. Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. We want to make your online experience satisfying and safe. 
> 
> Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it. 
> 
> We invite you to contact us if you have questions about this policy. You may contact us by mail at the following address: 
> 
> ABOUND ENTERPRISES  
>  P.O. Box 800907  
>  Valencia, CA  
>  91355
> 
> Or, you may contact us by [eMail](http://www.onlinemerchantforum.com/forums/sendmessage.php) or via Private Message.
> 
> Additional Information: Terms of Service
> 
>  **INFORMATION THIS SITE GATHERS AND TRACKS**  
>  ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM gathers two types of information about users: 
> 
> Information that users provide through optional, voluntary submissions. These are voluntary submissions to receive our electronic newsletters, to participate in our message boards or forums, to email a friend, and from participation in polls and surveys: 
> 
> Information ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM gathers through aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites. This information allows us to better tailor our content to readers' needs and to help our advertisers and sponsors better understand the demographics of our audience. Under no circumstances does ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM divulge any information about an individual user to a third party. 
> 
> ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM Gathers User Information In The Following Processes: 
> 
> **Optional Voluntary Information**
> 
> We offer the following services, which require some type of voluntary submission of personal information by users: 
> 
> 1\. Message boards/forums 
> 
> Users of the site's Message Boards and Forums must register for these services in order to post messages, although they needn't register to visit the site. During registration the user is required to supply a username, password, and email address. 
> 
> 2\. Electronic newsletters (Dispatches) 
> 
> We sometimes email members an electronic newsletter. Members may remove themselves from the mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page.
> 
> 3\. Polling 
> 
> We may offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what our audience thinks about important issues. Opinions or other responses to polls are aggregated and are not identifiable to any particular user. ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM may use a system to "tag" users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users. 
> 
> 4\. Surveys 
> 
> ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM may occasionally conduct user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our sponsors, advertisers and partners. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party. 
> 
> **Children**
> 
> Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent. 
> 
> **Usage tracking**
> 
> ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM tracks user traffic patterns. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM does break down overall usage statistics according to a user's domain name, browser type, and MIME type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user's browser). 
> 
> ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enter in our Search function, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. 
> 
> **Cookies**
> 
> We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above). 
> 
> Tracking cookies may also be placed on your computer when you click on a sponsor's ad.
> 
> You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you do need cookies to participate actively in message boards, forums, polling and surveys.
> 
> **Donations**
> 
> When using the donations system, ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM may keep a record of the member id and the donation amount. This information is nevery published or shared. Because all donations are accepted through paypal, absolution no credit card or any other kind of payment information or personally identifiable information is ever gathered or retained by ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM.
> 
> **Subscriptions**
> 
> When purchasing a paid subscription, ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM may keep a record of the member id, the subscription amount and the subscription term. This information is never published or shared. Because all subscription payments are accepted through paypal, absolution no credit card or any other kind of payment information or personally identifiable information is ever gathered or retained by ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM.
> 
>  **USE OF INFORMATION**  
>  ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users. 
> 
> As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, surveys, message boards, and forums. ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM never shares newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners. 
> 
> When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters. 
> 
> ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM does not track the usage patterns of individual users, including who clicks on a given ad. It should be noted that advertisers will have their own policies for tracking visitors, but they do not share this information with ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM, beyond the commission they pay us for successful referrals. We will not disclose any information about any individual user except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 
> 
> **SHARING OF THE INFORMATION**  
>  ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our advertisers better understand our audience's demographics. We will not share information about individual users with any third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. **SECURITY**  
>  ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our members/customers. **OPT-OUT POLICY**  
>  We give users options wherever necessary and practical. Such choices include: 
> 
> Opting not to receive our electronic newsletters. 
> 
> Opting not to participate in certain interactive areas, which completely alleviates the need to gather any personally identifiable information from our users.
> 
>  **YOUR CONSENT**  
>  We collect the following information:   
> 
> 
>   1. Click-stream data
>   2. HTTP protocol elements
>   3. Search terms
>   4. User's Name
>   5. Computer information
> 
At the user's option, we may also collect the following data:   
> 
> 
>   1. Birth Date
>   2. Email Address
>   3. Telephone
>   4. Business Address
> 
This data will be used by ourselves and our agents. 
> 
> By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by ONLINE MERCHANT FORUM. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.
